A Guide to the University of Virginia Fall Convocation Addresses, 1976-1998, 2002, 2015
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Fall Convocation Addresses 1976-1998, 2002, 2015
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-30/9/2.061
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These speeches were transferred from the University of Virginia Office of Major Events to the University of Virginia Library on various dates.
Scope and Content
The collection contains copies of seventeen addresses delivered at the University of Virginia, 1976-1998, 2002, 2015. There are speeches delivered by Bernard Mayo, 1976; Hugh Scott, 1977; William Styron, 1983; Charles McDowell, 1984; Robert M. O'Neil, 1985; Norman A. Graebner, 1986; Henry Abraham, 1987; Richard Rorty, 1991 (incomplete); J. Jackson Walter, 1992; Rita Dove, 1993; R. K. Ramazani, 1994; Richard Guy Wilson, 1995; Bonnie Guiton Hill, 1996 (draft and revised); Jahan Ramazani, 1997; Robert L. Kellogg, 1998; Janine Jagger, 2002; and, Gregory B. Fairchild, 2015
The collection also contains a tape of the Styron address.
There is also a speech delivered by University of Virginia president Robert M. O'Neil to incoming students in 1986.
The collection includes a list of convocation speakers, 1976-1998, compiled by the University of Virginia Office of Major Events.
Arrangement
The speeches are arranged in chronological order.
Contents List
- Bernard Mayo, Professor Emeritus of History 1976 (Folder 1)
- Senator Hugh Scott, 1977 (Folder 2)
- William Styron, 1983 (Folder 3)
- Charles McDowell, columnist for Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1984 (Folder 4)
- Robert M. O'Neil, [1985] (Folder 5)
- Norman A. Graebner, 1986 (Folder 6)
- Henry J. Abraham, James Hart Professor, 1987 (Folder 7)
- Richard Rorty, 1991 (Folder 8)
- J. Jackson Walter, 1992 (Folder 9)
- Rita Dove, 1993 (Folder 10)
- R. K. Ramazani, 1994 (Folder 11)
- Richard Guy Wilson, Commonwealth Professor of Architectural History, 1995 (Folder 12)
- Bonnie Guiton Hill, Dean of McIntire School of Commerce, 1996 (Folder 13)
- Jahan Ramazani, Faculty in English Department, 1997 (Folder 14)
- Robert L. Kellogg, Faculty in English Department, 1998 (Folder 15)
- Janine Jagger, MPH, Ph.D., 2002 (Folder 16)
- Gregory B. Fairchild, E. Thayer Bigelow Associate Professor of Business Administration at the Darden School of Business, 2002 (Folder 17)